to drive the solutions. So let's talk about what business should do. And when I say that, you probably think that I'm going to talk about corporate philanthropy or corporate social responsibility. CSR is the norm today, and it's very useful.
para impulsar las soluciones. Hablemos de lo que deberían hacer las empresas. Y cuando digo eso, probablemente piensan que hablaré sobre filantropía corporativa o de la responsabilidad social corporativa. La RSC es la norma hoy, y es muy útil.
It provides a route for corporate generosity and that generosity is important to many corporations' employees and customers. But you know what? It's just not big enough, or strong enough, or durable enough to drive solutions to the biggest problems in our world today because it's incremental cost. Even when business is booming, CSR just isn't designed to scale. And then of course in a downturn, it's one of the first programs to be cut. So no,
Proporciona una ruta para la generosidad corporativa y esa generosidad es importante para los empleados de muchas corporaciones y clientes. ¿Pero saben qué? Simplemente no es lo bastante grande, lo bastante fuerte o lo bastante resistente para impulsar soluciones a los mayores problemas actuales de nuestro mundo porque se trata de un costo incremental. Incluso cuando el negocio está en auge, la RSC simplemente no está diseñada para escalar. Y luego, por supuesto, en una recesión es una de las primeras cosas que se recortan. Así que
CSR -- corporate social responsibility -- isn't the answer, but TSI -- total societal impact, is. TSI is the sum of all of the ways business can affect society by doing the real work: thinking about their supply chains, working on their product design and manufacturing processes and their distribution. The real work of business, when done with innovation, can actually create core business benefits for the company and it can solve the meaningful problems in our world today. So what does TSI look like? Focusing on TSI means incorporating social and environmental considerations. And you know what? It's something that isn't completely new. It's been thought about for a while. But the hard part is that corporations almost exclusively still think about something called TSR: total shareholder returns. But TSI -- total societal impact -- needs to stand alongside TSR as an important and valid driver of corporate strategy and corporate decision-making. And we've got the data to show you why and how. Some companies are already making this happen. They're beginning to make it happen. So let me tell you the story about Mars. Mars is the sixth-largest private company in the United States. If you're like me, they make some important products, like coffee and chocolate. So not surprisingly,
la CSR, la responsabilidad social corporativa, no es la respuesta, pero sí el TSI, el impacto social total. El TSI es la suma de todas las formas de negocio que puede afectar a la sociedad haciendo el trabajo real: al pensar en sus cadenas de suministro, al diseñar sus productos, procesos de fabricación y su distribución. El verdadero trabajo de los negocios tras haber terminado con la innovación, realmente puede crear beneficios comerciales centrales para la compañía y puede resolver los problemas significativos actuales de nuestro mundo. Y, ¿cómo es el TSI? Si nos centramos en el TSI, significa incorporar consideraciones sociales y ambientales. ¿Y saben qué? Es algo que no es completamente nuevo. Ya fue pensado hace un tiempo. Pero la parte más difícil es que las empresas siguen pensando casi exclusivamente en algo llamado TSR: el rendimiento total para los accionistas. Pero el TSI, el impacto social total, necesita estar al lado del TSR como un importante y válido impulsor de la estrategia corporativa y la toma de decisiones corporativas. Y tenemos los datos para mostrarle por qué y cómo algunas compañías ya hacen que esto suceda. Están logrando que esto suceda. Así que déjenme contarte la historia de Marte. Marte es la sexta compañía privada más grande de EE. UU. Si son como yo, pensarán que Marte hace algunos productos importantes, como el café y el chocolate. Así que no sorprende
one of their most important ingredients is cocoa. And some of their competitors are actually really worried about the sustainability and the availability of cocoa supplies. But not Mars. They're confident in the stable supply of that crop for the long term. And why is that? It's because they partner with NGOs around the world that are working with small shareholder farmers. And those certification agency's NGOs are working to help farmers improve crop yields, they're making sure that they get a fair, premium, livable wage and they're helping them address any human rights potential issues in supply chains, and they're helping minimize the effects on the environment, like deforestation. Mars is on a path to 100 percent certified cocoa, so this is a good program for farming communities, it's a good program for the environment, and it's a good program for Mars, who has solved a significant risk in their supply chain. But now let's get to the data, because it's actually really awesome. And let me explain exactly what the data points I'm going to talk about are. When analysts and financial people look at companies, they think about a lot of different statistics. I want to talk about two of the most important ones.
que uno de sus ingredientes más importantes sea el cacao. Y algunos de sus competidores realmente están preocupados sobre la sostenibilidad y disponibilidad de suministro de cacao. Pero no en Marte, porque confían en el suministro estable de ese cultivo a largo plazo. ¿Y por qué esto es así? Es porque se asocian con ONGs de todo el mundo que trabajan con pequeños agricultores accionistas. Y las ONGs de esas agencias certificadas trabajan para ayudar a los agricultores a mejorar el rendimiento de los cultivos, asegurándose de que reciban un salario justo para vivir. Y les ayudan a abordar todo problema potencial de derechos humanos en las cadenas de suministro, y ayudan a minimizar los efectos sobre el medio ambiente, como la deforestación. Marte está en el camino de lograr el 100 % de cacao certificado. Se trata de un buen programa para comunidades agrícolas, es un buen programa para el medio ambiente, y es un buen programa para Marte, quién ha resuelto un riesgo significativo en su cadena de suministro. Pero veamos los datos, porque son realmente increíbles. Y déjenme explicar exactamente qué tipo de datos son de los que hablaré. Cuando los analistas y las personas financieras miran las compañías, piensan en muchas estadísticas diferentes. Quiero hablar de dos de las más importantes.
I'm going to talk about the overall value of a company -- its valuation -- and I'm going to talk about its margin. Basically the difference between all of its earnings and all of its costs. So in our study, we looked at oil and gas companies, and the oil and gas companies that are performing most strongly on TSI -- total societal impact -- see a 19 percent premium on their valuation. 19 percent. When they do really well on things like minimizing the impact of their company on the environment and water, and when they have very strong occupational health and safety programs. And when they also add in strong employee training programs, they get a 3.4 percentage point premium on their margins. But what about other industries? Biopharmaceutical companies that are the strongest performers on TSI see a 12 percent premium on their valuation. And then if they're best at expanded access to medicines -- making medicines available for the people who need them -- they see a 6.7 percentage point premium on their gross margins. For the retail banks that are strongest on TSI, they see a three percentage point premium on their valuation, and then for those that differentially provide financial inclusion -- access to financial products for people who need it -- they see a 0.5 percentage point premium in their net income margin. Now, these numbers for banks may not seem very big, but in highly competitive industries, even really small differences in margin matter a lot. Now, what about those consumer goods companies -- the ones who make those products we love like coffee and chocolate? Consumer goods companies that perform best on total societal impact see an 11 percent valuation premium. And then if they do those smart things with their supply chain -- inclusive and responsibly sourcing their product -- they see a 4.8 percentage point premium on their gross margins. These numbers are significant. We've long known that things like fundamental financials, growth rates and financial risks are key drivers of valuation, but this rigorous analysis shows that social and environmental factors -- total societal impact measures -- are also linked to valuations and margins. Wow. All else equal -- we didn't confuse the analysis with anything. All else being equal, companies that perform strongly on social and environmental areas achieve higher margins and higher valuations. Now, I do understand that companies are under a lot of short-term earnings pressures. But fortunately, the investors who create some of this pressure are actually more and more themselves starting to think longer-term and starting to think with this TSI lens. In our conversations and surveys with investors, 75 percent of them say they expect to see improved revenues and improved operating efficiency for companies that are thinking with a TSI lens. And they're actually starting to incorporate this in their own investing behavior. Last year, 23 trillion in global assets were in the category of socially responsible investing. Now, that's five billion over just the last two years. And it represents a quarter of the total global assets managed in the world. I know that some of you may be cringing a little bit right now. Because in my decades of strategy consulting with businesses and NGOs and governments around the world, I find that many businesspeople are hesitant to talk or even sometimes think about
Voy a hablar sobre el valor general de una empresa: su valoración. y voy a hablar sobre su margen. Básicamente es la diferencia entre todas sus ganancias y todos sus costos. En nuestro estudio, analizamos las compañías de petróleo y gas, y las compañías de petróleo y gas con mayor TSI, es decir, con mayor impacto social total. Así hay una prima del 19 % en su valoración, 19 %. cuando lo hacen realmente bien minimizando el impacto de su empresa en el medio ambiente y el agua, y cuando tienen programas muy fuertes de salud y seguridad ocupacional. Y cuando también agregan programas sólidos de formación de empleados obtienen una prima de 3.4 puntos porcentuales en sus márgenes. Pero, ¿y otras industrias? Las empresas biofarmacéuticas con los mejores resultados en ETI ven una prima del 12 % en su valoración. Y luego, si son mejores para expandir el acceso a los medicamentos, es decir, que logran que los medicamentos estén disponibles para las personas que los necesitan ven una prima de 6.7 puntos porcentuales en sus márgenes brutos. Para los bancos minoristas que son más fuertes en TSI, ven una prima de tres puntos porcentuales en su valoración, y luego para aquellos que ofrecen inclusión financiera diferencialmente acceso a productos financieros para las personas que lo necesitan, ven una prima de 0.5 puntos porcentuales en su margen de ingreso neto. Estos números para los bancos pueden no parecer muy grandes, pero en industrias altamente competitivas, incluso las pequeñas diferencias en el margen importan mucho. Y, ¿qué pasa con esas empresas de bienes de consumo las que hacen los productos que nos encantan como el café y el chocolate? Las empresas de bienes de consumo con mejor rendimiento en el impacto social total logran una prima de valuación del 11 %. Y luego, si hacen esas cosas inteligentes con su cadena de suministro, abastecimiento inclusivo y responsable de su producto, ven una prima de 4,8 puntos porcentuales en sus márgenes brutos. Estos números son significativos. Hace tiempo que sabemos que cosas como finanzas fundamentales, las tasas de crecimiento y los riesgos financieros son los principales factores de valoración. Pero este análisis riguroso muestra que los factores sociales y ambientales, las medidas totales de impacto social, también están vinculados a valoraciones y márgenes. Guau. Todo lo demás continúa igual, no confundimos el análisis con nada. En igualdad de condiciones, empresas con gran rendimiento en áreas sociales y ambientales logran mayores márgenes y valoraciones más altas. Entiendo que las empresas están bajo gran presión por obtener ganancias a corto plazo. Pero afortunadamente, los inversores que crean algo de esta presión en realidad cada vez más ellos mismos comienzan a pensar a más largo plazo y a pensar con esta lente TSI. En nuestras conversaciones y encuestas con inversores, el 75 % de ellos dice que espera ver una mejora en los ingresos y una mejor eficiencia operativa para las empresas que están pensando con una lente TSI. Y en realidad están comenzando a incorporar esto en su propio comportamiento de inversión. El año pasado, 23 mil millones en activos globales estaban en la categoría de inversión socialmente responsable. Eso significa 5 mil millones en los últimos dos años. Lo que representa una cuarta parte del total de activos globales gestionados en el mundo. Sé que algunos de Uds. se estarán encogiendo de hombros en este momento. Porque en mis décadas de consultoría estratégica con empresas, ONGs y gobiernos de todo el mundo, encuentro que muchos empresarios dudan en hablar o incluso en pensar
the business benefits of doing good. They somehow think it's going to negate the value of the benefits they're creating for society. Or that they'll be perceived as heartless or even mercenary. But we really do need to think differently. We need to think differently because the only way we're going to make substantial progress on the challenging problems of our time is for business to drive the solutions. The job of business is to meet customer needs and to do so profitably. They need to to survive. So one of the best ways for businesses to help ensure their own growth, their own longevity, is to meet some of the hardest challenges in our society and to do so profitably. And when they do that innovatively, when they do that ethically, responsibly, incredibly, they should be proud. But if you still aren't sure about this, let's talk about a few more examples. What if you're a technology company and you're trying to grow your platform and you're trying to grow your customers? Like, Airbnb. Airbnb has a portfolio of total societal impact activities. They're all spot-on their core business. In one initiative, they're helping enable their community to provide housing for free to those in disaster: crisis survivors and relief workers. In another effort on their part, they're actually helping and working with NGOs to ensure that people can provide housing for free for refugees.
sobre los beneficios comerciales de hacer el bien. De alguna manera piensan que negarán valor a los beneficios que están creando para la sociedad. O que serán percibidos como desalmados o incluso mercenarios. Pero realmente debemos pensar diferente. Necesitamos pensar diferente porque la única forma en que lograremos un progreso sustancial en los desafiantes problemas de nuestro tiempo es que las empresas impulsen las soluciones. La misión de las empresas es satisfacer las necesidades del cliente y hacerlo de manera rentable. Se necesita para sobrevivir. Y, una de las mejores maneras para que las empresas ayuden a asegurar su propio crecimiento, su propia longevidad, es enfrentar algunos de los desafíos más difíciles en nuestra sociedad y hacerlo de manera rentable. Y cuando lo hacen de forma innovadora, cuando lo hacen de forma ética, responsable, increíble, deberían estar orgullosos. Pero si aún no están seguro de esto, veamos algunos ejemplos más. ¿Qué pasa si eres una empresa de tecnología e intentas hacer crecer tu plataforma y tu cartera de clientes? Como Airbnb. Airbnb tiene una cartera de actividades de impacto social total. Todos son puntuales en su negocio principal. En una iniciativa, ayudan a habilitar su comunidad para proporcionar viviendas gratis a aquellos envueltos en tragedias: sobrevivientes de crisis y trabajadores humanitarios. En otro esfuerzo de su parte, en realidad ayudan y trabajan con ONGs para garantizar que las personas puedan proporcionar viviendas gratuitas a refugiados.
Now, what I love about this program is that I don't think most people would've figured out
Lo que me encanta de este programa es que no creo que la mayoría de la gente se habría dado cuenta de cómo expresar su generosidad
and open their homes for those in such dire need -- certainly not so quickly or so easily or efficiently -- without this innovation by Airbnb. But at the same time, this is core to their corporate strategy and core to their growth because they grow by increasing the number of hosts and guests using their platform. But if they'd only been thinking exclusively about the return side of things, I'm not sure they would have ever figured out this route to growth, because they're not charging transaction fees. So it's a pretty exciting way, when they were thinking about how to bring their capabilities to a need in society and at the same time drive their own growth. But what if you're trying to find new customer segments? Let's move to South Africa, and let's talk about Standard Bank. In South Africa, the government has a regulation
abriendo sus hogares a aquellos en necesidad extrema, ciertamente no tan rápido o tan fácil o eficientemente, sin esta innovación de Airbnb. Pero al mismo tiempo, esto es esencial para su estrategia corporativa y fundamental para su crecimiento porque crecen al aumentar la cantidad de alojados e invitados usando su plataforma. Pero si solo hubieran pensado exclusivamente en retorno de inversión, no creo que alguna vez habrían descubierto esta ruta hacia el crecimiento, porque no cobran tarifas de transacción. Y es una forma muy emocionante cuando estaban pensando en cómo aplicar sus competencias a una necesidad en la sociedad y al mismo tiempo impulsar su propio crecimiento. Pero, ¿qué sucede si se trata de encontrar nuevos segmentos de clientes? Cambiemos a Sudáfrica, y hablemos de Standard Bank. En Sudáfrica, el gobierno tiene una regulación
that requires all banks to donate 0.2 percent of their profits to small and medium black-owned enterprises. And many banks just donate this to the entrepreneurs, but Standard Bank thought creatively. And what they did is they took those funds and they invested them in an independent trust, and they used that trust to fund loans to these black entrepreneurs. This is a highly leveraged model. They can support a lot more entrepreneurs with capital, and because their success is completely intertwined with the success of the entrepreneurs, they're actually also using the fund to provide technical assistance. More entrepreneurs supported, more people and communities being lifted out of poverty. And it's successful for Standard Bank. So successful that they're actually working on expanding this program
eso requiere que todos los bancos donen el 0.2 % de sus ganancias a pequeñas y medianas empresas con propietarios negros. Y muchos bancos simplemente donan esto a los empresarios, pero Standard Bank pensó creativamente. Y lo que hicieron es tomar esos fondos y los invirtieron en un fideicomiso independiente, y usaron esa confianza para financiar préstamos a estos empresarios negros. Este es un modelo muy apoyado. Este facilita el apoyo a muchos más empresarios con capital, y su éxito está completamente relacionado con el éxito de los empresarios, en realidad también utilizan el fondo para proporcionar asistencia técnica. Con más empresarios apoyados, hay más personas y comunidades sacadas de la pobreza. Y es exitoso para Standard Bank. Tan exitoso que en realidad están trabajando para expandir este programa
to other areas in their portfolio. It's not like we haven't been trying to solve the problems in our world for a long time. We have, and they're still here. We're making progress, but it's not far enough, or fast enough, or universal enough. We need to flip our thinking. We need to have business -- both companies and investors -- bring creative, innovative corporate strategy and capital to solving the biggest problems in our world. And when they do that innovatively, and when they do that with all of their thinking and all of their strategy and all of their capital, and they're creating both total shareholder returns and total societal impact, we know that we will solve those problems, both profitably and generously. Thank you. (Applause)
a otras áreas en su cartera. No es que no hayamos intentado resolver los problemas en nuestro mundo por mucho tiempo. Lo hemos hecho y seguimos haciéndolo. Estamos progresando, pero no es suficiente, lo bastante rápido, o lo bastante universal. Necesitamos cambiar nuestro pensamiento. Necesitamos tener empresas, compañías e inversores con una estrategia corporativa creativa y capital para resolver los mayores problemas en nuestro mundo. Y cuando lo hacen de forma innovadora, y cuando lo hacen con todos sus pensamientos y toda su estrategia y todo su capital, crean rendimientos totales para los accionistas además de impacto social total, sabiendo que resolveremos esos problemas, tanto de manera rentable como generosa. Gracias. (Aplausos)